□ +49 1525 1487189 | ■ nvnkmrpdy@gmail.com | □ nvnkmrpdy | □ nvnkmrpdy | ■ nvnkmrpdy

Summary_

I'm a Scala developer who believes in continuous learning. I like working with microservices, functional programming, distributed systems, and software design.

I most recently worked at Monedo where I built and maintained the Scoring Engine to assess the credit-worthiness of a customer.

Skills

In Regular Use: Scala, Java Familiar: Python, C, C++ **Programming Languages**

Scripting: Shell, Javascript

Tools: Elasticsearch, MongoDB, RDBMS (PostgreSQL), RabbitMQ, Redis Frameworks & Technologies

Libraries: Scala - Akka Toolkit, Cats, ZIO, Distage, Circe; Java - Struts 2.0, Hibernate 3.0, EJB 3.0

Docker, Jenkins, GitLab CI/CD, Terraform, Amazon Cloud (AWS) **Tooling & Operations**

Experience

LetMeShip Hamburg, Germany

Feb. 2021 - Present SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Breaking down the existing monolithic application to microservices.
- Building up a new tech stack in Scala.

enfore Hamburg, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - BACKEND Nov. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- · Added features to the existing services.
- Simplified the build pipeline in Gitlab CI/CD.
- Worked on the BCM (Business Continuity Management) task.

Monedo Holding GmbH (formerly Kreditech Holdings SSL GmbH)

Hamburg, Germany Aug. 2017 - Oct. 2020

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Acted as a co-Tech Lead for the past 1 year for the Underwriting team.
- · Developed the Scoring Engine using Akka Streams that executes the decision tree from a score-card, consuming from and writing data to
- Built the Orchestrator component using Akka HTTP which orchestrates the dynamic selection and invocation of Data Science machine-learning models based on the assigned weight of the model, and generates the offer/rejection.
- · Developed several external service connectors that are invoked by the Scoring Engine to collect data of the customer using Akka HTTP.
- · Worked on the DataWriter and DataReader components developed using Akka Streams and Akka HTTP that streamlines the operations to MongoDB.
- · Deployed a centralized monitoring environment (Kibana Visualization, New Relic) which gathers system metrics as well as docker run-time metrics.

Nokia Networks Bangalore, India

R&D ENGINEER Apr. 2015 - Aug. 2017

- Implemented REST APIs for data handling and the support of configuring WiFi-AP in the Cloud-based Wireless LAN Controller.
- Helped build and maintain the features of the customer-facing UI web components.
- · Built dynamic reporting charts for the Cloud-WLAN controller administrator that shows the real-time metrics of the attached WiFi-APs.

Accenture Services Pvt. Ltd.

Bangalore, India

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING ANALYST

Jul. 2012 - Apr. 2015

- · Helped build and maintain features of the backend event-based Vehicle Tracking application built on message parsing.
- Designed REST APIs that facilitates the administrator users to send communication to any vehicle in their fleet and get their real-time status.
- Built the ETL pipeline over Pentaho Reporting suite.

Education

Anna University Chennai, India.

B.E. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Aug. 2008 - May. 2012

• One among top 15 teams in IBM TGMC 2011 software contest in India. • Organizer of the TEDx event, TEDxSonaCollege.

MARCH 28, 2021 Naveenkumar Perumal · Résumé